Hey everyone, thanks for listening to
the Grow Your Life podcast. My name is
Jeremiah Kowski and I've been helping
coaches, mentors, and trainers for the
last 22 years to scale their businesses
to reach more clients, make more money,
and live the life they've always wanted
to. Now, today I want to talk about one
of the single greatest behaviors of
success that's out there. And this is
not just a theory. This has evidence,
mountains of evidence, thousands of data
points to back this up.
across my own life, across the lives of
the multi-millionaire and even
billionaire clients that I've worked
with. And so,
what determines that you will have
success more than anything else? Well,
if we break it down to the smallest data
point, it's taking action. But that
doesn't quite give you the whole story.
What prevents us from taking action?
It's a lack of making a decision to take
action. And why often do we get stuck
making decisions to take action? Well,
the reason being is because we are so
focused on thinking about the process
and worrying about how something can go
wrong or what might not go how we want.
Many times it boils down to our need for
control. our need to control the
outcome, control how things are going to
go, control what's going to happen, that
we just do not make a decision, or we
sit and we wait until it feels right, it
feels perfect. Can I tell you that the
number one single greatest behavior for
success is the ability to make decisions
without having it all figured out,
without it feeling perfect, without
knowing exactly how it's going to turn
out and still making that decision to
move forward. I'm going to give you an
example. Well, yesterday I have had an
issue with my my car and I have to send
a uh demand letter to uh the dealership
that sold me the car. And
this was something that listen I don't
want to do. I'm not an expert in, but I
was able to use chat GPT to help me come
up with what to say, how to say it, all
those different things like that. And I
had to just pull the trigger. I just had
to get it done, map out the steps, and
do it. I couldn't wait another day,
another week to get this done.
And
I'll tell you, it it exhausted me. It
made me feel uneasy,
stressed, anxious, flooded, nervous,
whatever you want to say.
And yet, I had to still make the
decision to do the thing and it had to
get done by that time, that deadline
that I gave myself. And so, what it is
is the key is
making the decision to take action for
what you're going to do. Even if the
outcome is uncertain, it is 100%
uncertain what's going to happen with
this outcome, but I know that I need to
do it. And so because of that,
what helps us be successful is not
waiting until we have everything figured
out, till it feels like, okay, I know
that this is going to work out. I don't
have control over what's going to happen
in this scenario.
But what I do is I have control over the
actions that I can take
or my ability to not take an action
because I'm waffling around or afraid or
nervous or feel uncomfortable or feel
unsure or I'm
waiting until I know exactly what the
right thing to do is that's going to
produce the best result.
And this behavior,
I see so many coaches, mentors, even
people that I coach and mentor that deal
with this where they won't make a
decision because they're unsure. Is this
going to produce the result that I want
it to? Is this going to to do the thing
that I want it to do? And so, here's the
things that I I do. Often times, I'm not
waiting until I feel comfortable. I will
go through a process of calming my
nervous system down. Uh, but at the end
of the day, sometimes you just have to
do it scared. Sometimes you just have to
do it uncomfortable. Sometimes you just
have to take action when it feels like I
don't know what's going to happen. And I
can guarantee you, you have moments in
your life, you have situations in your
life where you have done these things
where you have taken action when you
were unsure how the outcome was going to
go, when it was almost certain that it
wasn't going to produce the best result,
but you knew that you had to do it. And
many times we wait until that's our
default. We wait until that's the only
thing that we can do.
Many times we wait until we have no
other option.
when in fact, what if you just shifted
the timeline where instead of waiting
until you have no other option, you did
that
right away.
And I'm sure you can come up with a
hundred reasons why it's not wisdom or
whatever it is that you're thinking. But
I will tell you that the speed of your
ability to make decisions about what to
do in your life and in your business
that you don't sit around that you don't
sit around waiting until you feel
comfortable. You're waiting until it
feels right or the right moment to do
everything.
And you develop that as not just a
habit, a behavior,
a personality,
and a way that you do everything.
and you shift into a place of being a
person who takes quick action without
having it all figured out.
You might say, "Well, you can't teach an
old dog new tricks. I I I just it's not
how I was raised. It's not what I was
taught in school."
Is that helping you reach the goals that
you want right now? Or do you feel
plateaued? And the reason why you feel
plateaued
is because you're letting your feelings,
your beliefs, your emotions dictate your
ability to be successful.
You have so much conviction
in the very thing that will make you
successful to not do it.
And I'm passionate about this because I
know
that this will change your life if you
do it. If you follow through with this,
if you take the risk
and you start shifting into that place.
I'll tell you another story. Listen, in
the beginning when you start doing this,
it might not go how you want and it
might take you a while to get
comfortable doing this and it might not
be in every part of your life.
But when you can grow past tiptoeing
through life
trying to make sure that you do all the
right things
and you give up this need where I I I
always do all the right things. I always
do all the right things.
It's not that you're intentionally
trying to do the wrong things. It's not
that you're intentionally trying to do
the bad thing, but you start moving on
intuition and instinct
more than, well, I spent all this time
processing and logically putting all the
pieces together.
If you can shift
your personality
into this place of doing what I'm
talking about, you will be unusually
successful. And this is the very thing
that I believe is the catalyst for most
people being successful. And they just
won't do it. It's the last thing that
they they're unwilling to give up. And
for me in my life, it was the last thing
I was unwilling to give up.
What changed it for me was when I have
two kids.
I don't have time to process and think
through every little thing or I wouldn't
have a life. I wouldn't have a business.
I wouldn't have the family that I want.
And so I had to create
and rebuild myself
mentally, emotionally to a place where
I'm somebody who takes action quickly.
Sometimes you could be seen as
recklessly.
That word reckless, we put so much
weight on the identity of I don't do
anything reckless.
When it comes to your marketing, when it
comes to sales, when it comes to you
building out your business,
reckless
action
as quickly as you come up with the
ideas,
not taking a ton of time to process
through it is going to make you more
successful than you ever imagined. And I
can look at back at my life. I can look
back at my business.
It's those are the times when I've been
the most successful financially. I've
had the most fulfillment.
And the times when I'm processing
through and trying to make sure I get it
right, those are when I've struggled.
Those are when I've had disappointment.
And so if you can shift where not just
like one moment, but you start to do
this in everything and you start to
really build this into your framework of
how you do everything in your life.
You're going to see changes that you
never possibly imagined. It's going to
feel uncomfortable. It's going to feel
something weird. It's going to feel like
I don't know how it's going to turn out.
I It's going to feel like I just can't
do this because this isn't me.
But you can do it.
That's built up in your head. Your
perception of reality is built up in
your head. It's not real. That
perception of reality of I can't do this
is built on a framework of multiple
beliefs over years that we've
established that are basically locking
us down. Imagine that you have a chain
that's tethering you to a previous
experience or a memory or a moment in
your past that's replaying itself. And
so you're tethered so much to that
memory in your past
that will not let you keep going be
because you have not resolved that and
you're so afraid of that past situation
happening again. or you're trying to be
wise so that you don't repeat a past
failure
and it's the very thing that's going to
actually repeat those failures for you.
It's the very thing that's actually
going to create those situations
happening again and again and again.
Working through these things from a
therapeutic and mental health standpoint
can also be very powerful. When I worked
with my therapist, I would literally
talk through the behaviors that I wanted
and then what I need to do to shift into
those behaviors and what is actually
preventing me from that. And we've f
realized again it's a lot of memories,
it's a lot of situations, it's a lot of
beliefs
that have tied us to I can't do this or
then when things don't go how we want,
I'm devastated. I'm just I can't believe
this didn't go how I wanted it to. and
you start to become comfortable
and excited with taking action and less
focused on it has to go my way.
You will see more success than you
imagined in your life. Okay? So listen,
start doing this.
Start doing it in every part of your
life, not just your business.
And watch what happens. Again,
it's not going to be an overnight thing
where you're just going to suddenly wake
up and every like you're everything you
do. It might be for some of you,
but you start doing it and and then
you'll notice, okay, I'm not doing it.
And then you'll do it a little bit more
and a little bit more and a little bit
more
and you will start to be successful. I
find that the times where I
struggle to do this are when I'm trying
to hold on to my success too tightly and
I'm trying to make sure that I don't
lose it. And that's the very thing that
causes us to lose the things. It becomes
a self-fulfilling prophecy where we
start losing the things that we've
worked so hard for because we're so
afraid of those things happening.
You can break out of this pattern. It
will change your life
in so many ways.
Listen, if this has helped you, I'd love
to work with you in my Wealthy Coach
Academy program where I work with
mentors, coaches, and trainers. Every
single week, I come alongside you and
show you exactly what steps to take to
build your business, exactly what to do
to market it, and to get more clients.
You can jump in. Go check out my website
at jeremicowski.com.
We'll talk soon. Have a good one.
[Music]
[Applause]